# Bilegjargal Jargalsaikhan "Jargal"

https://bilegjargal.github.io/portfolio

Email: bjargal56@gmail.com Mobile: +1-641-451-3892 http://linkedin.com/in/bilegjargal-jargalsaikhan

#### SUMMARY

Interested in all Javascript technologies. Experienced in enterprise system development using ReactJS, NodeJS, and the Agile/SCRUM software development method. Have an understanding of functional and object-oriented programming. Problem solver and a team player. Willing to work on both front-end and back-end components.

# SKILLS

- Frameworks: ReactJS, Angular, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Agile/SCRUM, Selenium, Jest
- Programming: Javascript(ES6), TypeScript, HTML, CSS, SASS, SQL, MongoDB
- Tools: Git, NPM, YARN, RESTful API, Ubuntu, Linux Mint

#### EXPERIENCE

**Career Note**: Completed on-campus studies and currently taking distance education courses to complete a Master's Degree in Computer Science(Available for full-time, W-2 employment)

## DIGITALWORKS COMPANY

Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia, Software Developer, Mar 2018 - Aug 2018

- Working as a full-stack software developer on a business tool for contract management, using ReactJS Redux,NodeJS, ExpressJS, and MongoDB, contributing to all phases of the software development process, including sprint planning, development, unit testing, iteration reviews, and deployment.
- Created a feature that generates a contract payment schedule by weekly, monthly or custom time interval with automatic invoice creation.
- Implemented a new function to add dynamic fields to a contract document. Resulted in a 30 percent reduction in the implementation time for new customer.
- Implemented CI/CD(continuous integration/continuous delivery) to my team using cucumber-Gherkin syntax. As a result our production delivery became more reliable and bug free.

## **ITZONE COMPANY**

Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia, Software Developer, Sep 2015 - Mar 2018

- Contributed to the development of a Supply Chain Management System and Customer Relationship Management System as part of a full ERP system. Used Javascript(ES6), C#, and Oracle SQL technology
- Created a back-end logic to compute all types of transaction flows over the finance and inventory modules, resulting in a 20 percent improvement in inventory and finance department workflows while completely eradicating faulty transactions.
- Modified SQL queries in order to speed up dynamic report load time by a factor of 8.
- On-site client development to quickly solve many major and minor bugs. Awarded Customer Happiness Award in the first quarter of the year.

#### **EDUCATION**

 Maharishi University of Management Master of Science in Computer Science; Fairfield, IOWA *Aug. 2018 – In progress* 

• Mongolian University of Management Bachelor of Science in Computer Science; Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia *Aug. 2012 – Jun. 2016*